Guide to the Cornell Cinema records, 1971-2000.
Cornell Cinema records
- Series I. Video Works
  - 17ème Parallele (La Guerre du Peuple) - Joris Ivens Format: VHS, V-8231 (Box 9)
  - Une Histoire de Vent - Joris Ivens - Joris Ivens Format: VHS, V-8232 (Box 9)
  - Power and the Land; Spanish Earth - Joris Ivens Format: VHS, V-8233 (Box 9)
  - La Seine a Rencontre Paris; A Valparaiso - Joris Ivens Format: VHS, V-8234 (Box 9)
  - The Afghan Alphabet - Mohsen Makhmalbaf Format: VHS, V-8235 (Box 9)
  - How Samira Made the Blackboard - Mohsen Makhmalbaf Length: 1:13:00 Format: VHS, V-8236 (Box 9)
  - Repertory Cinema: Past, Present, Future (a panel discussion) Format: VHS, V-8237 (Box 9)
  - Repertory Cinema: Past, Present, Future (a panel discussion) Format: VHS, V-8238 (Box 9)
  - Dottie Gets Spanked; Night Ride (preview copy) - Todd Haynes; Garrison Andrew Length: 56:11, V-8239 (Box 9)
  - Family Remains; A Psychic Mom (preview copy) - Tamara Jenkins; Ainsworth Shelli Length: 56:19, V-8240 (Box 9)
  - Artist Portrait Videos - Charlie Ahearn Length: 1:17:00 Format: VHS, 1991-1998; V-8241 (Box 9)
  - Cornell Student Films 1987 tape 1 Format: VHS, V-8242 (Box 9)
  - Cornell Student Films 1987 tape 2 Format: VHS, V-8243 (Box 9)
  - Cornell Student Films 1988 tape 1 Format: VHS, V-8244 (Box 9)
  - Cornell Student Films 1988 tape 2 Format: VHS, V-8245 (Box 9)
  - ZoNa - Pierre Desir, Ithaca College Filmmaker Format: VHS, 1999; V-8246 (Box 9)
  - You; Out in the Garden - Vincent Grenier Length: 30:00 Format: VHS, 1990-1991; V-8247 (Box 9)
  - 1993 Media Ithaca Festival-part 1 Length: 1:31:45 Format: VHS, V-8248 (Box 9)
  - 1994 Media Ithaca Festival-part 2 Length: 1:23:50 Format: VHS, V-8249 (Box 9)
  - For Cornell Cinema: Smoke Gets in Your Eyes; A Few Short Skits - Leah Shafer; Zacben Alex Format: VHS, 1999; V-8250 (Box 9)
  - Ithaca Compilation Format: VHS, 1918-1981; V-8251 (Box 9)
    Collection of films made in Ithaca or about Ithaca
  - News 10 coverage of Cornell's Anit-Apartheid protest Spring 1985 (include raw footage) Format: VHS, V-8252 (Box 9)
  - Home Movie: a diary for my American-born son - Miso Suchy Length: 52:00 Format: VHS, 2003; V-8253 (Box 9)
  - The Silver Screen: Color me Lavender - Mark Rappaport Length: 1:40:00 Format: VHS, 1997; V-8254 (Box 9)
  - Red Hollywood - Thom Anderson and Noel Burch Length: 1:58:07 Format: VHS, 1996; V-8255 (Box 9)
  - Underground Zero - Jay Rosenblatt and Caveh Zahedi Length: 75:41 Format: VHS, 2002; V-8256 (Box 9)
  - Beckett Directs Beckett: ENDGAME - Beckett Length: 1:36:00 Format: VHS, 1992; V-8257 (Box 9)
  - To New Horizons: Ephemeral Films 1931-1945 Format: VHS, 1987; V-8258 (Box 9)
  - Beatrice Fairfax Vol. 1 (1916) - Wharton Studios Inc. Format: VHS, V-8259 (Box 9)
  - The Lottery Man (1916) - Wharton Studios Inc. Format: VHS, V-8260 (Box 9)
  - If Women Only Knew (1920) - Cayuga Pictures Format: VHS, V-8261 (Box 9)
  - Hands on a Hard Body - S.R. Bindler Format: VHS, V-8262 (Box 9)
  - Synthetic Pleasures - Iara Lee Format: VHS, 1995; V-8263 (Box 9)
  - Looking for Langston - Issac Julien Length: 45:00 Format: VHS, 1989; V-8264 (Box 9)
  - Minerva's Machine: Women and Computing - John Friedman Format: VHS, V-8265 (Box 9)
  - Black Athena Length: 1:00:00 Format: VHS, 1991; V-8266 (Box 9)
  - Homophobia in Hollywood Format: VHS, 1992; V-8267 (Box 9)
  - Ready for the House; Interlaced Format: VHS, V-8268 (Box 9)
  - Flat is Beautiful - Sadie Benning Length: 50:00 Format: VHS, 1998; V-8269 (Box 9)
  - Relocations and Revisions: the Japanese American Internment Reconsidered Length: 30:00 Format: VHS, 1992; V-8270 (Box 9)
  - Diverse Reports: Standard Techniques & The Badung File: Right to Reply Format: U-Matic, V-8017 (Box 10)
  - Badung File: Soyinka, Wole Length: 40:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8018 (Box 10)
  - Badung File: Dasilva Dasilva Format: U-matic, V-8019 (Box 10)
  - Consuming Hunger Part 1: Getting the Sory Length: 29:13 Format: U-Matic, V-8020 (Box 10)
  - Bandung File: Taken for a Ride Length: 30:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8021 (Box 10)
  - Consuming Hunger Part 3: Selling the Feeling Length: 29:22 Format: U-Matic, V-8022 (Box 10)
  - Commission - Woddy Vasulka Length: 45:00 Format: U-Matic, 1983; V-8023 (Box 10)
  - Color Adjustment part I Length: 48:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8024 (Box 10)
  - Color Adjustment part II Length: 40:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8025 (Box 10)
  - John Canemaker Sample Reel (animations, commercials), from Elmira born artist Format: U-Matic, V-8026 (Box 10)
  - Consuming Hunger Part 2: Shaping the Image Length: 29:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8027 (Box 10)
  - Katherine Dieckmann Format: U-Matic, V-8028 (Box 10)
  - Pete & Pete - Katherine Dieckmann Format: U-Matic, V-8029 (Box 10)
  - Information Withheld - Juan Downey Format: U-Matic, V-8030 (Box 10)
  - Return of the Motherland - Juan Downey Length: 27:10 Format: U-Matic, V-8031 (Box 11)
  - Looking Glass, The - Juan Downey Length: 28:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8032 (Box 11)
  - Hallwalls Performance Program Tape 1: Excerpts 1981-1985 Format: U-Matic, V-8033 (Box 11)
  - Hallwalls Performance Program Tape 2: Steven Griffith, Tony Billoni, Fritz Bacher Format: U-matic, V-8034 (Box 11)
  - Broken English - Derek Jarman Length: 20:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8035 (Box 11)
  - Don't Start Me To Talking - Stevenson J. Palfi Length: 42:37 Format: U-Matic, V-8036 (Box 11)
  - Pete & Pete spots - Katherine Dieckmann Format: U-Matic, V-8037 (Box 11)
  - Hard Times and Culture Part One, Vienna Fin-de-Siecle - Juan Downey Format: U-Matic, V-8038 (Box 11)
  - J.S. Bach - Juan Downey Length: 28:22 Format: U-Matic, 1986; V-8039 (Box 11)
  - The Hole Format: VHS, V-8151 (Box 11)
  - The Sanguinaires Format: VHS, V-8152 (Box 11)
  - The Wall (Le Mur) Format: VHS, V-8153 (Box 11)
  - Tamas & Juli Length: 61:24 Format: VHS, V-8154 (Box 11)
  - The Book of Life - Hal Hartley Format: VHS, V-8155 (Box 11)
  - Life on Earth Format: VHS, V-8156 (Box 11)
  - First Night of My Life Format: VHS, V-8157 (Box 11)
  - Susceptible to Kindness Miss Evers' Boys and the Tuskegee Syphilis Study Format: VHS, 1994; V-8271 (Box 11)
- Series II. Printed Materials
  - Uris Library Media Department Videos and Films, 1988-1991 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Video distribution catalogs, 1983-2000 (Box 12, Folder 2-4)
    Includes distributors Electonic Arts Intermix, Picture Start, Video Data Bank, Frameline Distribution, The Kitchen, The Video Project, Museum of Modern Art
  - Video distribution catalogs - zine format, 1993-1998 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Includes distributors Paper Tiger Television, Art Com, One Way Films, Drift Distribution, Video Out, Alternative Filmworks
  - Exhibition catalogs, 1988-1990 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Catalogs of media art exhibitions co-sponsored by Cornell Cinema and the Johnson Museum: Media Buff: Media Art of Buffalo, NY (1988), and Border Crossings: The Cinema of Johan van den Keuken (1990). 2 copies of each.
  - Cinema ticket, Undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Calendars and Posters, 1971-1983
    Folders are chronologically organized by calendar year, rather than Cornell's academic year.
    - Campus Calendar, 1971-1972 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1971-09 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1971-10 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1971-11 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1971-12 (Folder 1)
    - Fritz the Cat poster, 1972 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1972-01 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema/University Union calendar, 1972-02 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema/University Union calendar, 1972-03 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema/University Union calendar, 1972-03-26-1972-04 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1972-05 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1972-08-1972-09 (Folder 1)
      Includes note about the start of Cornell Film Club
    - Cornell Cinema/University Union calendar, 1972-10 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1972-11 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1972-12 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1973-01 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1973-02 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1973-03 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1973-04 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1973-05 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, Summer 1973 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1973-08-1973-09 (Folder 1)
      Count: 2
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1973-10 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1973-11 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1973-12 (Folder 1)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1974-01-1974-02 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1974-03 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1974-04 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1974-05 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, Summer 1974 (Folder 2)
      Count: 5
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1974-08-1974-09 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1974-10 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1974-11 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1974-12 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1975-01 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1975-02 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1975-03 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1975-04 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1975-05 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, Summer 1975 (Folder 2)
      Count: 6
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1975-10 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1975-11 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1975-12 (Folder 2)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1976-01 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1976-02 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1976-03 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1976-04 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1976-05 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, Summer 1976 (Folder 3)
      Count: 7
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1976-09 (Folder 3)
      Includes explanation of price increase for tickets; Count: 2
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1976-10 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1976-11 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1976-12 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1977-01 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1977-02 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1977-03 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1977-04 (Folder 3)
    - Taking Off series poster, 1977-04-01-1977-04-10 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1977-05 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, Summer 1977 (Folder 3)
      Count: 4
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1977-09 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1977-10 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1977-11 (Folder 3)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1977-12 (Folder 3)
    - Space Shuttle Orbiter poster, 1978 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1978-01 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1978-02 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1978-03 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1978-04 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1978-05 (Folder 4)
    - The Man who Loved Women, 1978-05-12-1978-05-13 (Folder 4)
    - Allegro Non Troppo, 1978-05-12-1978-05-20 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, Summer 1978 (Folder 4)
      Count: 3
    - Film Club calendar, Fall 1978 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1978-09 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1978-10 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1978-11 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1978-12 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1979-01 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1979-02 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1979-03 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1979-04 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1979-05 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1979-06 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1979-08-1979-09 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1979-10 (Folder 4)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1980-01 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1980-02 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1980-03 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1980-04 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1980-06 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1980-07-1980-08-12 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1980-11 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1981-02 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1981-03 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1981-08-1981-09 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1981-10 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1982-10 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1982-11 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1983-04 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1983-06 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1983-08-1983-09 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1983-10 (Folder 5)
    - Cornell Cinema calendar, 1983-11-1983-12 (Folder 5)
    - Brooktondale Apple Festival, 1975-10-18-1980-10-18 (Folder 6)
    - Cornell Law Students' Association square dance poster, 1973-02-24-1979-02-24 (Folder 6)
    - Samurai Film Series poster, Undated (Folder 6)
    - A Gillis photography exhibit poster, Undated (Folder 6)
    - Moliere's The Miser poster, Undated (Folder 6)
    - Cornell Widow's Deep Throat poster, Undated (Folder 6)
    - Film Club calendar, Undated (Folder 6)